appfolio.com 2019-07-10

# Privacy Policy

**APPFOLIO, INC. PRIVACY POLICY**

LAST UPDATED: JANUARY 17, 2019

AppFolio, Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively, "we", "us", "our" and/or "AppFolio") understand that personal information is important to you, and we take your privacy concerns seriously. We have crafted this Privacy Policy with those foundational principles in mind, and have endeavored to clearly describe the ways we collect, store, use and protect personal information across our various platforms. With that said, we understand that you may have questions regarding this Policy and/or other issues related to data privacy and protection, and invite you to email us anytime at [privacy@appfolio.com](mailto:privacy@appfolio.com).

In light of constantly evolving data privacy laws, rules, regulations and industry best practices, we must reserve the right to revise this Policy from time to time. When we do so, we will modify the "Last Updated" date listed above. Further, if we deem any change material in our sole and absolute discretion, we may post a related notice in our software and/or contact you by electronic mail. Regardless, your continued use of our websites, including without limitation [www.appfolioinc.com](https://www.appfolioinc.com/), [www.appfolio.com](https://www.appfolio.com/), [www.mycase.com](https://www.mycase.com/), [www.roostrentersinsurance.com](http://www.roostrentersinsurance.com/) and related sites (collectively, the "Websites"), and/or any of our Services (as that term is defined on our Terms of Service), shall constitute your acceptance of any revisions we make.

**COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL AND NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION**

AppFolio collects certain information about you in the course and scope of providing access to its Websites and/or Services. We also collect information about others that you provide us in connection with your use of our Services. For example, we collect certain personal information that you voluntarily provide, typically including without limitation names, email addresses, company name, certain geographical information and contact telephone numbers, whether via our Websites or our Services, and however accessed (e.g., desktop, laptop, mobile or any other device). We also collect information you provide via telephone or electronic mail and, in some cases, in the course of in-person interactions with us. This permits us to communicate with you about our Services and related topics and better understand how individuals access and use our Services.

In addition to information you voluntarily provide to us, we also automatically collect certain non-personal, technical information about you and/or your devices as you interact with our Websites or Services, and we store that information in log files. For example, we may collect your IP address, browser type, internet service provider, operating system, click stream data, the pages you view on any or all of our Websites, the pages you view before and after viewing our Websites and any search terms you use on any of our Websites. This permits us to recognize you and personalize your experience on our Websites, and, more generally, to improve our Websites and Services as a result of any learnings we may glean from information collected.

We may also collect information about you from third parties who already have your information in their possession, custody or control, as part of our normal outbound marketing efforts.

**COOKIES**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies to make your experience easier for you by saving your preferences while you are at any of our Websites. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and as such, you will find them at most major websites. By showing how and when visitors use our Websites, cookies help us see which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to our Websites are based on data we collect, such as total number of visitors and pages viewed. This information is most easily tracked with cookies. We use the information from cookies to better tailor our Websites and Services to our users’ needs.

**OUR CUSTOMERS’ BUSINESS DATA**

Our customers use our Services to host commercially and personally sensitive information related to their businesses. That information is confidential and, in some cases, proprietary, to our customers. As such, we do not review, share, distribute or reference any such information except as necessary to provide the Services in a professional manner consistent with our legal, regulatory and other obligations, and subject to our Terms of Service; and to better understand how customers and other individuals access and use our Services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, to improve our Services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other internal research and analytical purposes.

Further, we may share certain personal information with our third party vendors if necessary to provide Services to our customers. For example, all financial, credit, and billing information that we collect is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective customers for various Services and, where appropriate, to bill for those Services.

We may also occasionally engage third parties to provide certain Services to our customers and/or, in turn, their customers. Further, we may provide certain Services jointly with selected business partners. In such circumstances, third parties and partners are not permitted to retain, share, store or use your information for any other purpose than to deliver the relevant Service(s) in a professional manner, and consistent with their legal, regulatory and other obligations.

For clarity, we do not and will not share any personally identifiable or sensitive business information with third parties for unknown reasons.

**ANONYMOUS USAGE DATA**

We collect certain information about how different constituencies (e.g., our customers, our customers’ customers, vendors, etc.) interact with our Services on an anonymous basis. For example, we collect certain information designed to help us understand how our customers manage their properties within AppFolio Property Manager. In that case, the information we collect does not include information that could identify you personally.

We may anonymize the information we collect about your use of our Services by removing or "hashing" any data fields (such as name, address and telephone number) that identify you or that can be used to identify you personally. We use industry best practices and state-of-the-art techniques to anonymize and aggregate data.

We aggregate information by combining anonymous data that meet certain criteria into groups. For example, we might want to know average rental prices for a particular market so as to better understand how to communicate with our property manager customers and prospects in that market or so that we can communicate more broadly about market trends by region or similar issues. The resulting data aggregation would be an anonymized aggregated total that we could then share without disclosing any personal or sensitive information. For clarity, we do not and will not sell your usage data to third parties.

**ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION**

If you have any questions regarding your personally identifiable information, or you’d like to correct and/or update any such information, please contact us at [privacy@appfolio.com](mailto:privacy@appfolio.com).

**LEGAL DISCLAIMER**

Notwithstanding the foregoing, we reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable or other information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

**COMMUNICATION MATTERS**

**Special Offers, Updates and Research**

We will occasionally send information regarding our Services, including without limitation educational offers and our newsletter, to our customers and/or prospective customers. We also may occasionally contact you, your customers or other third parties related to you to inquire how you or such individuals use our Services and how we might improve our Services. We typically use names, email addresses and telephone numbers to send these communications and make these contacts. Out of respect for your privacy, if you’d prefer not to hear from us, you can choose not to receive these types of communications or contacts. Please see the section entitled "Choice and Opt-out" below.

**Services-related Announcements for Users**

We often send our customers announcements for new or augmented Services. For instance, as we add software enhancements to our Services, we may send you an email notification. Many of these emails or other communications are necessary for the continued optimal functionality of our Services.

**Public Forums, Referrals and Testimonials**

We may provide public forums such as bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on our Websites or within our Services subject to certain Terms of Use. These forums are provided as a service to our customers and other users to help them exchange ideas, tips, information and techniques related to our Services. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

You may also use our referral program to inform friends about our Websites and Services. When using the referral program, we request your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend an invitation to visit one or more of our Websites.

We also post a list of users and testimonials on our Websites that may contain information such as the users’ names and titles. We obtain the consent of each user prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

**Choice and Opt-Out**

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, or if you do not wish for us to contact you, your customers or related third parties for our own internal research purposes, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, or by emailing us at [privacy@appfolio.com](mailto:privacy@appfolio.com). You may also contact us by phone at 899.700.8299 or via postal mail: AppFolio, Inc., 50 Castilian Drive, Goleta, CA 93117.

**SECURITY**

The privacy and security of your information is important to us. We utilize robust security measures to protect customer data from unauthorized access. Sensitive data is encrypted and website connections are protected using strong Transport Layer Security (TLS). Our Websites are hosted in a secure server environment that uses multi-layer perimeter security including firewalls and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Website(s) and to read the privacy statements of each and every website you visit that collects personally identifiable information.

**EXTERNAL LINKS (THIRD PARTY WEBSITES)**

Our Websites and/or Services may contain links to third party websites. These third party websites maintain their own policies regarding cookies and the collection and use of personal and non-personal information. We assume no responsibility or liability for the actions of such third parties with respect to their collection or use of your information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of every website that you visit, including those you may reach through a link on our Website(s) or in our Services.

**BUSINESS TRANSITIONS**

In the event AppFolio goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by or combination with another company, or a sale of all or a portion of our assets, your personally identifiable information and any personally identifiable information you provided to us about others will likely be among the assets transferred.

**EUROPEAN UNION GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION**

We exclusively market and sell our Services to United States-based organizations and individuals. Even though we do not intentionally collect information about residents of the European Union ("EU"), some EU residents' data may be inadvertently collected through marketing channels or by virtue of our customers’ legitimate use of our Services. Collection and storage of any EU resident's data by us is minimal and incidental. No such data is used for marketing or any other purpose.

Further, we do not intentionally collect information on individuals under 18 years of age, regardless of their residency. Incidental exposure to this information may be possible if, for example, our customers upload this information to one of our Services or it is inadvertently captured by our marketing organization.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, if you are an EU resident and would like to request that your data be securely removed from our systems, however collected, please send an email with proof of EU residency to [privacy@appfolio.com](mailto:privacy@appfolio.com). We will remove all relevant data, so long as that removal is technically feasible, does not impact the legitimate accounting or business practices of our customers, and does not violate other regulatory or legal standards with which we must comply. We will also cooperate with our customers in good faith to address any requests they receive or that may impact them directly.

**CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this Policy, please contact us at [privacy@appfolio.com](mailto:privacy@appfolio.com), or send a letter to AppFolio, Inc., 50 Castilian Drive, Goleta, CA 93117, Attn: Data Privacy. We’re looking forward to hearing from you.
